http://www.miltenyibiotec.com/US-en/privacy-statement.html

Miltenyi Biotec is happy to announce that we are again fully operational. In case there are issues getting in contact with us, please use an alternative contact number. Read moreClose
Products
Applications
Resources
Support
About us
HomePrivacy statement
Products
Applications
Graft engineering
CliniMACS CD34 Reagent System (FDA-approved)
Cell manufacturing platform
Clinical flow cytometry
CliniMACS Prodigy
CliniMACS Buffer
CliniMACS Plus
CliniMACS Reagents
Accessories
MACS GMP Portfolio
Productfinder
Explore our comprehensive range of high quality products.
Promotions
See all of our current offers and say hello to our happy cells.
All protocols
T cells
B cells
Dendritic cells, monocytes, macrophages
NK cells
Pluripotent stem cells
Hematopoietic stem cells
Mesenchymal stem cells
Graft engineering
CliniMACS CD34 Reagent System (FDA-approved)
Cell manufacturing platform
Overview
Clinical flow cytometry
CliniMACS Prodigy
CliniMACS Buffer
CliniMACS Plus
CliniMACS Reagents
Accessories
Productfinder
Explore our comprehensive range of high quality products.
Promotions
See all of our current offers and say hello to our happy cells.
Applications
All protocols
T cells
B cells
Dendritic cells, monocytes, macrophages
NK cells
Pluripotent stem cells
Hematopoietic stem cells
close
Find the products and resources you are looking for!
Search / order no.
For exact search enclose your search term with "quotation marks". Enter an "AND" between multiple search terms. Add an " * " behind your search term for full wildcard search.
Get in touch!
Our local employees are always happy to answer your questions. Highly trained and experienced teams in your country can provide quick, helpful, and comprehensive support.
Miltenyi Biotec distribution:
As a global market leader with numerous subsidiaries and distributors, Miltenyi Biotec is
committed to providing our customers around the world with the highest quality products.
In addition to direct selling in more than 20 countries in North America, Europe and
Asia/Pacific, Miltenyi Biotec also provides support for our customers through an
extensive distributor network covering dozens of additional countries.
Search
Search / order no.
For exact search enclose your search term with "quotation marks". Enter an "AND" between multiple search terms. Add an " * " behind your search term for full wildcard search.
Wishlist
Contact
Country
As a global market leader with numerous subsidiaries and distributors, Miltenyi Biotec is
committed to providing our customers around the world with the highest quality products.
In addition to direct selling in more than 20 countries in North America, Europe and
Asia/Pacific, Miltenyi Biotec also provides support for our customers through an
extensive distributor network covering dozens of additional countries.
Cookie Settings
We use cookies in order to provide the best possible website experience for you.
This includes cookies that are technically required to ensure a proper functioning of the website,
as well as cookies which are used solely for anonymous statistical purposes,
for more comfortable website settings, or for displaying personalized content.
You are free to choose the categories you would like to permit. Please note that depending on your settings,
the full functionality of the website may no longer be available. Further information can be found in our Privacy Statement.
Manage Preferences
Accept all
ComfortShow more detailsShow less details
Technically required cookies
This category of cookies is required to ensure a proper functioning of the website.
Statistics
This category of cookies is needed to see how users use our website and how we can improve the website.
All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.
Comfort
This category of cookies is needed to find out how a new website design performs and improve our website.
Confirm selection
Accept all
Privacy statement
Privacy statement
Thank you for your interest in our company and our products. Miltenyi Biotec takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. Due to statutory provisions, we are obliged to inform you about the type, scope and purpose of the collection and use of personal data. Therefore, we would kindly ask you to acknowledge the following information.This Privacy Statement describes and governs the information collection, use, and sharing practices of Miltenyi Biotec B.V. & Co. KG and its corporate affiliates, subsidiaries, and divisions as may change from time to time (collectively, “Miltenyi,” “we,” “us,” and “our”) with respect to Miltenyi’s websites, mobile applications, and other services, irrespective of digital or analog, that link to this Privacy Statement (together, the “Services”).Before you submit any information on or through the Services, please carefully read this Privacy Statement. By using any part of the Services, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as further outlined in this Privacy Statement. We will continue to evaluate this Privacy Statement as we update and expand the Services and our offerings, and we may make changes to the Privacy Statement accordingly. Any changes will be posted here and you should check this page periodically for updates. Your continued use of the Services will signify acceptance of the terms of the updated Privacy Statement.Please note that this Privacy Statement applies to information collected through the Services and to information collected offline but not to information you may provide to any third-party sites to which Miltenyi may link, except as expressly provided herein. This Privacy Statement applies regardless of the device used to access the Services (e.g., personal computer, mobile device, consumer electronics device, or any other technology or software known today or developed in the future). Some services offered by or affiliated with Miltenyi may be governed by a separate privacy statement. In those instances, the product-specific privacy statement shall apply to that service.
1. Name and address of the controller
The following body is responsible according to the statutory provisions related to data privacy and data protection:Miltenyi Biotec B.V. & Co. KGFriedrich-Ebert-Straße 6851429 Bergisch GladbachGermanyPhone: +49-2204-8306-0Fax: +49-2204-85197E-Mail: macs@miltenyibiotec.de
2. Name and address of the data protection officer
The following person is the designated data protection officer of the controller:If you have any problems, questions or ideas, please contact :Data Privacy Officer / DatenschutzbeauftragterMiltenyi Biotec B.V. & Co. KGFriedrich-Ebert-Strasse 6851429 Bergisch GladbachGermanyE-Mail: dataprivacy-MiltenyiBiotec@legitimis.comIf you like to know what data we have stored about you please forward your request to this mail box:dataprivacyRfI@miltenyibiotec.de.
3. General Information on data processing
a. Scope of the processing of personal dataWe collect and use personal data of our users only to an extent which is necessary to provide a functional website as well as display our content and provide our Services. The collection and usage of personal data of our users is generally based on the consent of the user. An exemption is made in these cases where obtaining consent is not possible based on factual grounds or where statutory provisions allow the usage of personal data.
b. Legal basis for the processing of personal dataWhere the data subject gives a consent, this consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. a Regulation(EU) 2016/679- “GDPR”).Where the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract, this necessity is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR).Where the processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the controller is subject, this necessity is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. c GDPR).Where the processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party and where the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data are not outweighed, this necessity is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR).
c. Processing of special categories of personal dataIf we need to process special categories of personal data (i.e. personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, and the processing of genetic data, biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation) and will ask for your consent in each case separately.
d. Transfer of personal data within the Miltenyi Group Miltenyi processes personal data, like customer data and employee’s personal data, outside the EU and the EEA, so called third countries, in particular in the countries where our affiliated companies are seated, if required for internal administrative purposes or for the performance of a contract. We process the personal data according to a group company data processing agreement based on the EU Standard contractual clauses and in compliance with applicable laws. If we use service providers in a third country, they are obligated to comply with the data protection level in the EU by agreement of the EU standard contractual clauses. The transmitting personal data within the Miltenyi group for internal administrative purposes, including the processing of customers’ or employees’ personal data is our legitimate interest. This necessity is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. f and recital 48 GDPR).
e. Erasure and storage periodThe personal data of the data subject is erased or the processing is restricted as soon as the data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected.Personal data may also be stored where Union law or Member State law to which the controller is subject allows such storage. The personal data of the data subject is erased or the processing is restricted as soon as a storage period runs out except for the cases where there is a necessity of storage of the personal data for the performance of a contract or to comply with statutory law requirements.
4. Provision of the Services and the creation of logfiles
Whenever you use our Services, our webserver automatically stores data of the client computer. The following data is collectedInformation on the browser and its version The computer operating systemThe Internet Service Provider The IP-address Date and timeReferring websiteWebsites which are visited through our systemThis data is stored in the logfiles of our webserver. This data is not combined with other personal data of our users. The legal basis for this storage are our legitimate interests in such storage (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR). The data is stored to maintain the functionality of our Services. The data is also used to optimize our Services and maintain the security of our webserver. The data is erased after 10 days. A longer storage may occur, but in this case IP-addresses of the user are anonymized or deleted. The collection and storage of personal data is necessary to provide our Services. Thus, an objection by the data subject is not possible. Furthermore, the IP-address is used to automatically detect the geographical region of the user. Based on this localization, the Services are automatically tailored to the user, i.e. language settings for the region of the user. This usage of the data creates a better user experience on our Services.
5. Usage of Cookies
Our website uses Cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored in the browser of the user or stored by the browser on the computer system of the user. Whenever a user visits our website, a cookie may be stored. This cookie contains of a characteristic string which allows the identification of the user the next time he visits our website. The following data is stored in our cookies:
Miltenyi Biotec website (www.miltenyibiotec.com)
Cookie groupNameDescriptionDurationTechnically required    MILTENYI_APPLICATIONThis cookie stores the information of the user’s login status only when the user is logged in and/or if there is something in the user’s cart. This information is used to display a badge on the corresponding menu icon.Session MILTENYI_CART_COOKIEThis cookie stores a random hash number that is associated with a guest user’s cart or a logged in user’s shop id. It is used to show the correct cart to a user.Session MILTENYI_SSOThis cookie stores a unique user id after a registered user logs into Azure. The cookie is used to check the login status of the user.Session MILTENYI_COUNTRYStores chosen country20 years XSRF_TOKENThis cookie stores a security token to defend against cross-site-request-forgery attacks.  miltenyi_live_sessionThis cookie is a Laravel session cookie that stores an ID. It is used to be able to store a guest cart.Session invoiceUnitIdThis cookie saves the id of the last selected or first in the list Macs Pick Up Point unit for a customer. This is used to ensure that the correct data for a unit is served on the invoice page.Session inventoryUnitIdThis cookie saves the id of the last selected or first in the list Macs Pick Up Point unit for a customer. This is used to ensure that the correct data for a unit is served on the inventory page.Session transactionUnitIdThis cookie saves the id of the last selected or first in the list Macs Pick Up Point unit for a customer. This is used to ensure that the correct data for a unit is served on the transaction page.Session displayCookieConsentThis cookie stores one number that indicates if the user has consented to cookie storage yet or not. It is checked on every page load and triggers the display of the cookie consent bar at the top of the page if the user has not consented.2 years Neos_SessionThis cookie stores the unique ID of the NEOS CMS user session. It’s used by the website to differentiate sessions.Session PHPSESSIDThis cookie stores the unique ID of the PHP session. It’s used by system to differentiate PHP sessions.Session cookieConsentSaves information which cookies and cookie groups have been accepted.2 years cookieConsentAcceptedSaves a version of the cookie layer, to only display the cookie layer, when a new version has been published.2 yearsStatistics    displayCookieConsentUsed to check cookie layer confirmation.2 years Neos_SessionSession ID of NeosSession _gaUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.2 years _gidUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.24 hours _gatUsed by Google Analytics to throttle request rate. Google Analytics is deployed via Google Tag Manager, this cookie will be named _dc_gtm_<property-id>.1 minute mf_[session]Cookie for identifying the browser session.Session mf_userChecking if the user is new or returning visitor.90 daysComfort    WYSIWYG_AB_TESTING This cookie saves the automatically made decision (a or b) and name for all A/B-tests on the website in a raw JSON string. When a user visits the page initially the cookie is checked for missing and new A/B-tests and they are added to it. If the user visits a page that contains an A/B-test the cookie is checked for the decision value and the corresponding version is displayed.2 years displayMaintenanceInfoConsentThis cookie stores a number which will be used to not display a maintenance layer after a consent.10 hoursPersonalization    nQ_cookieIdIdentify user1 year nQ_visitIdIdentify user session1 year
Moving Image video player
Cookie groupNameDescriptionDurationStatistics    HTML_BitRateBucketCsvPlayback time of video player per visitor by bitrateSession AkamaiAnalytics_BrowserSessionIdID of Browser SessionSession HTML_isPlayingCountAmount of video playbacksSession HTML_VisitIntervalStartTimeStart of interval between visitors of websiteSession HTML_VisitCountCookieAmount of visitorsSession HTML_VisitValueCookieValue of visitors of websiteSession
Fluorofinder panel builder
Cookie groupNameDescriptionDurationStatistics    _gaUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.2 years _gatUsed by Google Analytics to throttle request rate.Request _gidUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.1 day mp_[id]_mixpanelMixpanel Support1 yearComfort    _ffnext-sessionAn information store for functional use such as: which facility or machine was selected so that it can be pre-populated if the same user starts another panel, which panel id is currently in progress for navigation purposes, etc. Also stored in this cookie is an CSRF token to help ensure that requests to the application have originated from forms provided by the application (and are forgeries from another site).Session __insp_nvInspectlet support1 year __insp_padInspectlet support1 year __insp_sidInspectlet support1 year __insp_slimInspectlet support1 year __insp_targlptInspectlet support1 year __insp_targlpuInspectlet support1 year __insp_uidInspectlet support7980 years __insp_widInspectlet support1 year
Fluorofinder spectra viewer
Cookie groupNameDescriptionDurationStatistics    _gaUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.2 years _gidUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.1 day mp_[id]_mixpanelMixpanel Support1 yearComfort    _ffnext-sessionAn information store for functional use such as: which facility or machine was selected so that it can be pre-populated if the same user starts another panel, which panel id is currently in progress for navigation purposes, etc. Also stored in this cookie is an CSRF token to help ensure that requests to the application have originated from forms provided by the application (and are forgeries from another site).Session svViewHolds state of user’s spectra viewer view selection: “multi” or “combined”.Session
www.reafinity.com
Cookie groupNameDescriptionDurationTechnically required    cookieConsentSaves information which cookies and cookie groups have been accepted. Statistics    _gaUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.2 years _gidUsed by Google Analytics to distinguish users.1 day _gatUsed by Google Analytics to throttle request rate.1 minute dc_gtm_UA-XXX (equivalent to _gat)Google Analytics1 minute mf_[session]Cookie for identifying the browser session.Session mf_userChecking if the user is new or returning visitor.90 days _cfduidCollects and anonymizes End User IP addresses using a one-way hash of certain values so they cannot be personally identified.30 days _ga_XXXXXXXXXXGoogle Analytics2 years
The legal basis for the usage of these cookies are our legitimate interests in such usage (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR).We use cookies to provide a more user friendly experience. Some elements on our website require the browser to be identified after the user visits different pages on our website. Some functions of our website may not be operational if such cookies are not stored.Cookies are not stored by us, but by the user on his device. Thus, the user has full control of the cookies stored on his device and may delete them at any time. The user can also control which cookies are stored on his device.
6. Newsletter
We offer the (double opt-in) subscription to our newsletter. If the user decides to subscribe to our newsletter by clicking the subscribe button, a confirmation mail will be send out to the provided email address. The included unique URL must be confirmed by the user. The following personal data is collected and stored: E-Mail-AddressTitleAcademic titleFirst name, Last nameCountryThe collection of this data is needed to send out the newsletterThe following personal data is also collected and stored:Profile IDInterestsDate and time of the subscriptionThe collection of this data is needed to secure our systems against abuse.Our newsletter makes use of web beacon technologies to track usage. A tracking pixel in the newsletter and also embedded links within the newsletter containing an identifier link to our webpage and allow us to analyze your usage behavior and collect the relevant data to personalize our newsletter offer tailored to your interests.Your consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR). The legal basis for the tracking of usage is our legitimate interests in such usage (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR).The data is erased whenever a user unsubscribes from our newsletter. A user may unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe link provided.
7. User Accounts
Some of our Services require you to sign up for a Miltenyi user account. This Miltenyi user account will serve as a single sign on for the Services provided that require a sign up and may be used to make purchases in our webshop. We may use the name that you provide for your Miltenyi user account across all of the Services we offer that require a Miltenyi user account, so that you are represented consistently across all our services. We collect the following personal data and store it on our servers:NameTitleRoleAddressE-Mail-AddressTelephone numberInterestsThe collection of this data is needed to provide the user account. The user may at any time change or delete his personal data.The following personal data is also collected and stored:IP-addressDate and time of the registrationThe collection of this data is needed to secure our systems against abuse.Your consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR).When the account is used to make purchases in our webshop, the legal basis is the necessity for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract (Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR). The data is erased whenever a user deletes his user account. A user may delete his account at any time. You can opt-out the sign up for a Miltenyi user account however in this case you might not be able to fully use all functions on our website and Services provided.
8. Contact forms and E-Mail contact
Our Services offer contact forms which may be used to send messages to us. Furthermore we offer contact forms to provide Poster/AppNote downloads, Quote requests, Sample requests, Demo requests, Product information requests, Software updates/downloadsWhenever a user chooses to contact us through our forms, following personal data is collected and stored:TitleAcademic TitleFirst Name, Last NameE-Mail-Address of the userPhoneUniversity/CompanyInstituteDepartment/DivisionLab/Group/PIBuilding/Floor/RoomStreetCity, Zip CodeCountryThe collection of this data is needed to engage in a conversation with the user. Furthermore we use this data to provide you with product related information via newsletter.The following personal data is also collected and stored:IP-addressDate and time when sending a messageThe collection of this data is needed to secure our systems against abuse. Your consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR). The data is erased whenever the conversation with a user ends. A conversation has ended when we assume that the concern of the user has been solved.  A user may request the erasure of his personal data at any time by sending us a message. In this case, the conversation with the user cannot be carried on.
9. E-Commerce
We offer a webshop on our website to make purchases of our products. A user account is mandatory to make such purchases. During the purchase process, we highlight the Information required to make purchases as mandatory. Further personal data may be provided by choice.The following personal data is also collected and stored:IP-addressDate and time of the subscriptionThe collection of this data is needed to secure our systems against abuse.The legal basis for the collection and processing of this data is the necessity for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract (Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR).The processing of the personal data is needed to carry out the purchase, deliver the goods, to address warranty claims and due to fiscal requirements. Warranty claims can be made up to two years after the purchase. The fiscal regulations require storage of invoices for ten years. This necessity for compliance with a legal obligation to which the controller is subject is also the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. c GDPR).A user may request the correction of his personal data at any time. A user may also request the erasure of his personal data at any time. When the user has made purchases in our webshop, the personal data may be erased when there is no more necessity for the performance of the contract to which the data subject is party or when the applicable laws allow such erasure.When making purchases through our webshop, we may disclose the personal data of a user to third parties. This takes place in the following cases:To deliver parcels, packages or other mailings, we disclose the name and address of the user to the mail carrier we chose for delivery. The disclosure is necessary to perform the contract with the customer and the legal basis for the disclosure is Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR.To collect payments, we use third party payment providers. The user discloses his payment data to the provider who uses it to collect the due payment. The necessity arising from the contract with the customer is the legal basis for the disclosure (Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR).We offer the functionality to forward and share certain content with a friend or colleague. If you choose to use our sharing functionality to refer someone to our content, products or services, we will collect and use your information and that of the individual you are sharing with to send the content or link you request, but we do not store the information relating to the individual you wish to share with other than in connection with your request. Please note that we process the data on your behalf and that you remain the controller by meaning of the applicable Data Protection Law.Your consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR).
10. Social Media Plugins
Our website may offer third party social media widgets/tools/buttons. If you use third party sharing functionality, including social media widgets/tools/buttons, such use is subject to the third party’s privacy policy and terms.The usage of such social media widgets/tools/buttons leads to a disclosure of personal data to the provider of the social media widget/tools/buttons.We do not actively offer these functionalities. They have to be activated by the user to be used.Your consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR).
11. Third party content
Our Services may include third party content. Such content may consist of videos or maps. The usage of dedicated providers liberates us from the necessity to provide video streaming or geographical capabilities.When accessing third party content on our Services, personal data may be collected by the third party provider. This provider may at least be able to collect the following information:Information on the browser and its versionThe computer operating systemThe Internet Service ProviderThe IP-addressDate and timeReferring websiteThe legal basis for the implementation of third party content are our legitimate interests in such implementation (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR).
12. Third party tracking services and (re)marketing services
Our Services may include third party tracking services and (re)marketing services. Such services allow us to analyze the usage of our site, optimize it for our users and provide a better user experience.The legal basis for the implementation of third party services are our legitimate interests in such implementation (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR).
a. Google AnalyticsWe use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the Services analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Services (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. On behalf of the website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Services, compiling reports on Services activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore you can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB. This website uses Google Analytics for cross-device tracking by using a feature called User ID. You can deactivate the cross-device tracking in your Google Account: My Account/Your personal info. You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website:
Click here to opt out of Google Analytics.
b. Google Dynamic RemarketingThis website uses Google Remarketing and Google Signals. Google Remarketing and Google Signals are ad services from Google Inc. that target specific ads at previous visitors of the website.Third-party vendors, including Google, place ads on websites on the internet. They make use of cookies to place ads based on the user's previous visits to this website. Users are identified through cookies that are saved in the web browser. With the help of text files the usage of the website is analyzed and then used for specific product recommendations and interest-based advertising.If you do not want to receive interest-based advertising, you can use the Ads Preferences Manager to deactivate cookies from Google and adjust ads in the Google network by opening the Opt Out page in Google's ad settings (https://www.google.de/settings/u/0/ads?hl=de). Alternatively, users can deactivate the usage of cookies by third-party vendors by opening the Consumer Opt Out page of the Network Advertising Initiative or by deactivating the use of cookies in their browser.
c. DoubleClickDoubleClick uses cookies to support advertisers and publishers at managing and delivering ads on the web and to present relevant advertisements. The data gathered through the cookie about your usage of our website are only stored in a pseudonymous format using an identifier (e.g. a “Cookie ID”) and transferred to and stored on Google DoubleClick servers in the USA. Whenever you surf the web and see or click on an advertisement delivered or conveyed through the Google DoubleClick Ad Network, a DoubleClick cookie is stored in your web browser. If your web browser already has a DoubleClick Cookie, no additional cookie is stored.Additional information on the use of DoubleClick Cookies in the context of Google DoubleClick’s Ad Network can be found in the Frequently Asked Questions about Google DoubleClick’s Privacy Policy at google.com/intl/en/policies.
d. Google Tag ManagerThis website uses Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager is a solution operated by Google Inc., that allows marketed website tags to be managed using an interface. The Tag Manager tool itself (which implements the tags) is a cookie-less domain and does not register personal data. The tool causes other tags to be activated which may, for their part, register data under certain circumstances. Google Tag Manager does not access this information. If recording has been deactivated on domain or cookie level, this setting will remain in place for all tracking tags implemented with Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager does not set up any cookies for itself, only for the tools integrated through it.
e. MouseflowThis website uses Mouseflow: a website analytics tool that provides session replay, heatmaps, funnels, form analytics, feedback campaigns, and similar features/functionality. Mouseflow may record your clicks, mouse movements, scrolling, form fills (keystrokes) in non-excluded fields, pages visited and content, time on site, browser, operating system, device type (desktop/tablet/phone), screen resolution, visitor type (first time/returning), referrer, anonymized IP address, location (city/country), language, and similar meta data. Mouseflow does not collect any information on pages where it is not installed, nor does it track or collect information outside your web browser. If you'd like to opt-out, you can do so at https://mouseflow.com/opt-out. If you'd like to obtain a copy of your data, make a correction, or have it erased, please contact us first or, as a secondary option, contact Mouseflow at privacy@mouseflow.com.For more information, see Mouseflow’s Privacy Policy at http://mouseflow.com/privacy/.For more information on Mouseflow and GDPR, visit https://mouseflow.com/gdpr/.For more intormation on Mouseflow and CCPA visit https://mouseflow.com/ccpa.
f. Provide SupportThis website uses Customer Support Chat Service offered by Provide Support, LLC. Provide Support, LLC is fully committed to maintaining the privacy of all our customers. This service has support for industry-strength secure connection for chat sessions. When website visitors have questions or need help, they click on a Live Assistance button on the website, which opens a private chat messenger window. The visitor fills in the pre-defined information fields, adds a question, and then clicks on the "Start Chat" button. The customer service representative (operator) receives the call and reviews the information. If the call is accepted, the agent and site visitor communicate with each other via real time text messaging. Chat conversation transcripts are not stored on Provide Support chat servers. They remain on the chat server for the duration of the chat session and then destroyed.
g. Google Adwords Conversion TrackingThis website also uses Google Conversion Tracking, an analysis service by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; “Google”). In this process, a cookie is placed on your computer by Google Adwords (“conversion cookie”) if you have reached out website via a Google advert. These cookies lose their validity after 30 days and do not serve for personal identification. If you visit a specific website of ours and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google recognize that someone has clicked on the advert and was forwarded to our site. Every AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked via the websites of AdWords customers. The information obtained with the help of conversion cookies serve to create conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have decided on conversion tracking. AdWords customers are informed of the total number of users that have clicked on their advert and were redirected to page with a conversion tracking tag. They receive no information that could be used to personally identify a user. If you do not want to take part in tracking procedures you can also refuse the necessary cookie settings – via browser settings, which generally disable the automatic setting of cookies. You can also deactivate cookies for conversion tracking by setting your browser to block cookies from the domain “googleadservices.com” or by clicking on the following link and downloading and installing the plug in provided there: https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin. You will then be excluded from the Conversion Tracking statistics. If you do not want to receive interest-based adverts, you can also deactivate the use of cookies by Google for this purpose via the site https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/blocked-cookies.html or by clicking on the following link and downloading and installing the plug in provided there. https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin
You can find additional information and the Google data protection declaration at: http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/
h. Information about the consent to Albacross processing of personal data   On this website, data for marketing, market research and optimization purposes are collected and stored with Albacross on the basis of legitimate interests of the website operator (Art. 6 para.1 lit. f GDPR).We obtain your consent to the processing of personal data on the behalf of Albacross Nordic AB (“Albacross”). Information collected from cookies set in your device that qualify as personal data will be processed by Albacross, a company offering lead identification and ad targeting services with offices in Stockholm and Krakow. Please see below for full contact details. The purpose for the processing of the personal data is that it enables Albacross to improve a service rendered to us and our website (e.g “Lead Generation” service), by adding data to their database about companies. The data that is collected and used by Albacross to achieve this purpose is information about the IP-address from which you visited our website, and technical information that enables Albacross to tell apart different visitors from the same IP-address. Albacross stores the domain from form input  in order to correlate the IP-address with your employer. For the full information about our processing of personal information, please see our full Privacy Policy.  You may at any time withdraw your consent to this processing. Such withdrawal may be made either by contacting us, or by contacting Albacross directly.  Albacross Nordic AB Companyreg. no 556942-7338 Kungsgatan 26  111 35 Stockholm, Sweden  www.albacross.com - contact@albacross.com
i. Google Optimize and WYSIWYG A/B TestingWe also employ the Google Optimize service and WYSIWYG A/B Testing on our Website. Google Optimize and WYSIWYG A/B Testing allows us to use so-called A/B tests to reconstruct how various changes can affect a website (e.g. changes to input fields, design changes etc.). Cookies are stored on your device for these purposes. All data processed in this context are pseudonymous. Furthermore, we use Google Tag Manager to incorporate Google’s analysis and marketing services into our Website and to administer the same. If you do not want to receive interest-based adverts, you can also deactivate the use of cookies by Google for this purpose via the site https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/blocked-cookies.html or by clicking on the following link and downloading and installing the plug in provided there. https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin j. Supermetrics for Google Data StudioWe use Supermetrics for Google Data Studio as Data Processor. Through its connectors we process all Analytics data, collected by the tools described in the previous paragraphs, into Google Data Studio. When it comes to being a data processor, the data is never stored permanently on the systems of Supermetrics. In the majority of cases, the data is processed in real time. To improve performance, Supermetrics may cache the query results on their servers as needed for the success of your query. Please note that any time Supermetrics cache query results, data is strongly encrypted. Any caches are deleted once they are unnecessary or when use of the Supermetrics systems is ceased.The processed data is extremely restricted and not shared with any party.Supermetrics tools only use official APIs (application programming interfaces) for accessing data.Data transfers are done using SSL encrypted HTTPS connections.Supermetrics Oy (Finland) Company ID: 2552282-5 Mikonkatu 700100 HELSINKI, Finland Phone: +358 40 356 3260 E-Mail: privacy@supermetrics.comPrivacy Policy: https://supermetrics.com/privacy-policy-2018-5k. Firebase For the MACS Pick Up mobile app we use Firebase, a service provided by Google Inc. ("Google") to analyze and categorize user groups and to display push notifications on the basis of Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. Firebase is a platform that offers various services for mobile and web application operation.  We use Firebase  to provide information in our app (including database, storage, hosting and remote config services),to analyse user behavior within the app in all app interaction aspectsto send messages (cloud messaging services, notifications)In general, we do not collect personal information. All IP addresses will be anonymized. The use of firebase can be deactivated within the app.  You can find more information about Firebase at https://firebase.google.com/ Privacy shield: https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAITerms of use: https://firebase.google.com/terms/Data privacy: https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy/ & http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacyInformationen on third party provider: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001.l. LinkedIn Analytics and LinkedIn AdsWe use the conversion-tracking technology and retargeting functionality of LinkedIn on our website. This technology enables the display of personalized advertisements on LinkedIn after users have visited our website. In addition, it allows for the generation of anonymous analysis reports regarding the performance of ads as well as information about user interaction with our webpage. To do so, the LinkedIn Insight-Tag is incorporated in our webpage, which establishes a connection to the LinkedIn server when visiting our webpage, while in parallel being logged into a LinkedIn account.Further information about data storage and use, as well as rights concerning the protection of data privacy, can be found in the data privacy regulations of LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy). When logged into a LinkedIn account, the user can at any time deactivate tracking and data storage  (https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/enhanced-advertising).m. Facebook Custom AudienceWe use Facebook Custom Audiences on our webpage and therefore have integrated the so-called Facebook Pixel. This pixel enables the collection of pseudonymous information regarding the use of our webpage (e.g. information about which content was seen). This data can be used to place personalized advertisements on Facebook, for users that have a Facebook account.Further information about the extend and purpose of this data collection can be found in the data privacy regulations of Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). Data collection can be deactivated at any time (https://www.facebook.com/help/769828729705201/). Furthermore, the user is able to prevent the collection of data on this website by applying the following Opt-Out-Cookie: Deactivate Facebook Pixel.
13. Use of our “Miltenyi Brand Lab”
(1) The Miltenyi Brand Lab is the central platform for all marketing information and forms the basis of all communication under the Miltenyi brand. It is the starting point for when requesting, adapting, and ordering media materials of all kinds, and a source of knowledge and inspiration for employees, agencies, and any other participants (e.g. brand management, creation and editing of business cards, Word and PowerPoint templates).Digital and multimedia content, such as pictures, graphics, ads, flyers, banners, newsletters, slides, audio files, or videos are easy and quick to find, and can be converted automatically in the desired format for download, sending, or directly including into further marketing tools.With our Miltenyi Brand Lab, existing marketing material can be adapted quickly, easily, and independently. Without the need for any form of layout software, marketing material can be adapted for local use by the teams on the ground there, whilst ensuring brand consistency.(2) If you wish to use the Miltenyi Brand Lab, you must first request an access. To do this, you will need to provide some of your personal data. Information which is required for the creation of the account is indicated as such. Any additional information requested can be provided on a purely voluntary basis.Once your request is processed, you will receive your access information with a single-use password at the email address you have indicated. The password must be changed when you first log in.There are no core applications that require the processing of personal data as a primary function in the Miltenyi Brand Lab. However, your personal data may still be stored in various locations.Based on the principle of data minimisation, personal data should only be processed in accordance with the purpose and the amount limited.Usually, the use of the Miltenyi Brand Lab requires the processing of following categories of personal data:Information about the type of user, e.g., creator, editor, or publisherPersonal data within the specific client fields, e.g., agency employee, photographer, owner, etc.Assets/documents with a personal identifier, e.g., picture or signature, which are used for advertising purposesTechnical data, e.g., cookies or logs with IP data(3)  When you use the Miltenyi Brand Lab, we store your personal data, which is necessary for the performance of the contract, until you inform us to permanently delete your account. Additionally, we process personal data you have provided voluntarily for the duration of your use of the portal, unless you delete this data. You can manage or change any information in your protected client profile. The legal basis for the processing of your personal data is Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR.(3b) Where the data subject gives a consent, this consent is the legal basis for the processing of personal data (Art. 6 (1)  lit. a GDPR.(4) For our Miltenyi Brand Lab, we use the services of a third party provider. After in-depth research, we have chosen the BrandMaker Marketing Efficiency Cloud, created by the German provider BrandMaker GmbH, Rüppurrer Straße 1, 76137 Karlsruhe.The processing of personal data within the scope of the BrandMaker Marketing Efficiency Cloud mostly takes place in data centres in Germany. We have concluded a data processing agreement according to Art. 28 GDPR with BrandMaker GmbH.(5) To prevent third parties illegally accessing your personal data, the connection is encrypted through AES 256 und TLS 1.2.
14. Data Protection Information for the Use of Social Media
1. Online-PresenceThis is data protection information for the use of social media of the: Miltenyi Biotec B.V. & Co. KG Friedrich-Ebert-Straße 68 51429 Bergisch Gladbach Germany Phone: +49-2204-8306-0 Fax: +49-2204-85197 E-Mail: macs@miltenyibiotec.de 2. Data Protection OfficerWe have named a data protection officer whose contact information is: Data Privacy Officer / Datenschutzbeauftragter Miltenyi Biotec B.V. & Co. KG Friedrich-Ebert-Strasse 68 51429 Bergisch Gladbach Germany E-Mail: dataprivacy-MiltenyiBiotec@legitimis.com 3. Purpose of the Data Processing:We are present on several social media platforms in order to show ourselves, to make information available, to get in contact with users and communicate with them. 4. Processing of Personal Data:When visiting our various platforms of online-presence, we do not process any personal data directly.  However, the platform provider processes personal data.  Additionally, it is possible that, when using our social media platforms, we process personal data when the user actively provides it (e.g. when posting a comment). In particular, the data which is concerned is the username as well as information published on the user’s account. Furthermore, data on social media is usually processed for market studies and advertisement purposes. Thus, for example, through behaviour of the users and their interests, user profiles can be created. These user profiles can be used, for example, for advertisement purposes matching the users’ interests within the social media platform as well as outside of it. For these purposes, cookies are usually stored on the user’s device to store information about the users’ behaviour and interests. Additionally, data unrelated to the user’s device can be gathered from the user’s profile (especially if the user has an account on the platform and is logged in). For detailed information about the various processing activities and the objection possibilities, we advise you to verify the respective provider’s data protection policy. Please be advised: When visiting our social media, you are using the services and functionalities on your own responsibility. We do not have any influence on the art and scope of the respective data processing measures, type of processing, use of the data or the transfer of data to third parties. 5. Legal Basis:The processing of personal data through us is based on our legitimate interest regarding the presentation of the company to third parties as well as communication with users on our online platforms (Art. 6, 1. (f) GDPR). 6. Data transfers: We inform you that when using our social media platforms, personal data may be processed outside of the European Union. This can cause risks as, for example, the exercise of user rights may be more complicated. Details can be found in the data protection policies of the respective providers (see below). Regarding the US-providers which are certified under the US-Privacy Shield Agreement or with similar guarantees, we inform you that they thus have a duty to comply with the EU data protection requirements. We do not transfer data to third countries outside of the EU and EEA or to an international organisation, unless appropriate guarantees are set out. This includes European Standard Contractual Clauses (ESCC) as well as adequacy decisions through the EU Commission. 7. Our Presence in Overview: a. Facebook:When visiting our Facebook page, Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland (Parent company: Facebook, 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA) processes your personal data according to their data protection policy (https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy). Facebook is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield and thus obliged to comply with EU data protection requirements:  https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=ActiveAs a Facebook user, you have the possibility to adapt the advertisement settings of your Facebook account to determine how your use of our page may be analysed. Additionally, Facebook provides an objection form, available under: https://www.facebook.com/help/contact/1994830130782319. Further information regarting data protection: agreement for the joint processing of personal data under Art. 26 of the GDPR (joint with us, see contact information above: https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum.) The conditions of the use of our fanpage are determined according to Facebook’s general terms of use. Those conditions (including special conditions and guidelines) are available under:  https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms. Regarding analysis through Facebook pages, it is to noted that a collection and assessment can occur over several devices if they are being used by the same user while logged into their account to visit our Fanpage. The user statistics which are created are transferred to us in an exclusively anonymised form. There is no possible access to any of the personal data. Within our Facebook Fanpage, we use the Facebook service „Insights“ to acquire anonymised statistical information about the users of our Fanpage. The data protection information is available under:  https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/information_about_page_insights_data. When visiting our Facebook Fanpage, Facebook stores a set of information called a cookie on your device.  This cookie contains an assigned user code.  If this cookie is not deleted earlier it is active for 2 years. The user code can be linked with your personal data when you are registered as a Facebook user.  The information stored this way is processed by Facebook.  It is also possible that thirds get access to the cookie information from Facebook to provide advertisement on Facebook. Further information about the use of cookies through Facebook is available under: https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/. b. Twitter: The service provider is Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. The controller for people living outside of the US is: Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street, Dublin 2 D02 AX07, Ireland. Information about which data is processed by twitter and for which purposes can be found in Twitter’s data protection policy:  https://twitter.com/de/privacy. Information about the personalisation options and data protection settings are available under:  https://twitter.com/personalization. Twitter Inc. is certified as conforming with data protection requirements under the Privacy Shield:  https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active. In the general settings of your Twitter account and under the section „privacy and security“ you can restrict the data processing. Additionally, you can use the settings on your mobile device when using one (Smartphones, Tablets…) to restrict Twitter’s access to your contacts, calendar, photos, location, etc.  This depends on the operating system.  You can find further information about these elements on the Twitter Support page:  https://support.twitter.com/articles/105576#. You can find information about accessing your personal data being processed by Twitter under:  https://support.twitter.com/articles/20172711#.  Your can find information about the connections to you drawn by Twitter under:  https://twitter.com/your_twitter_data. You can request information through the data protection form or the archive request under:  https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170320#Please be aware of following recommendations: If you use the interactive functions on Twitter such as sharing (Retweeting), liking or commenting, is is on your own responsibility. If you send us a private or direct message on Twitter, it will be stored for 18 months. As a manager of a Twitter account, we have no influence on the use of analysis tools through Twitter and we do not have any information about it from Twitter. If analysis tools are used, please be informed that we have not agreed to it nor have we requested or in any way supported it. Additionally, any data acquired by Twitter is not made available to us. Only specific, non-personal information about the twitter activity is available for our twitter account such as the number of profile views or link clicks from a specific tweet. We have no possibility to restrict the use of possible analysis tools on our page.  d. Instagram:Instagram is a product of Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland (nachfolgend: „Facebook“). Information about the processing of personal data through Facebook is avaible on Instagram’s data protection policy under:  https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy. For the use of the service, the terms and conditions of Instagram (including any special conditions and guidelines) apply.  Those are available under:  https://help.instagram.com/581066165581870. When using the services, it is not to be excluded that your use of Instagram and data are shared with Facebook Inc. with headquarters in the US and processed there. Facebook Inc. is certified as data protection compliant under the EU-US Privacy Shied (see above, under Facebook). e. LinkedIn: LinkedIn is made available by LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland. The data protection policy is available under:  https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy. LinkedIn is certified as data protection compliant for transfers in the US under the EU-US Privacy Shied Agreement and it is thus not excluded that data is transferred there for processing:  https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000L0UZAA0&status=Active. You can object the use of the LinkedIn advertisement cookie under:  https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out. f. XING: XING is a service of XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg – Germany. The data protection policy as well as opt-out options are available under:  https://privacy.xing.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung8. Deletion of dataIf we process personal data of users, we only store it as long as necessary to complete the purpose for which it was collected or as long as legally required. Afterwards, the data is only stored for the duration of the legal storage period. 9. Your Rights as a Data Subject a. Right to Access At your request, you can have access without cost to the personal data we have stored about you. b. Your Rights to Rectification, Deletion, Restriction, and Objection If you no longer agree with the processing of your personal data or if the information is no longer correct, we will at your request, delete or block your data or have it corrected (within legal restrictions). The same applies if you wish for your data to only be processed in a restricted form. c. Your Right to Data Portability At your request, ye will transfer your personal data to a new controller in an accessible, structured and machine-readable format. d. Your Right to Lodge a Complaint with an Authority Ihr Beschwerderecht bei einer Aufsichtsbehörde You have a right to lodge a complaint with any authority:  https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.htmle. Your Right to Object your Consent with Future Impact If you have consented, you can object to any further future processing at any time. The prior processing on the basis of your consent is not affected. f. Restrictions Data that does not allow the identification of a person, for example anonymised for analysis purposes, is not impacted by these rights. Access, deletion, archiving, rectifying or transfer to another controller is also possible for this data is additional information is provide to allow identification.
15. Rights of the data subject
Every data subject has a right of access (Art. 15 GDPR), a right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR), a right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR), a right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR), a right to object (Art. 21 GDPR) and a right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR). The right of access and right to erasure are subject to the restrictions under sections 34 and 35 BDSG. Data subjects also have a right of appeal to a supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR in conjunction with section 19 BDSG). You have the right at any time to revoke your consent to the use of your personal data in the future. This also applies to consents that are granted prior to the entry into force of the EU General Data Protection Regulation, i. e., prior to 25 May 2018. Please be advised that the revocation will only take effect in the future. Any processing that was carried out prior to the revocation shall not be affected thereby. Again, just send an e-mail to the address given in the imprint or contact the Data Security Officer at the address above.  For example if you have provided contact information through the Services and decide that you do not want Miltenyi to use that information for marketing purposes in accordance with this Privacy Statement, you can opt-out of future use at any time by: (i) going to the link provided at the bottom of any email you receive and opting out of receiving future information; or (ii) by sending us an email at macs@miltenyibiotec.de. Please note that you may not be able to opt out of emails about your transactions and relationship with us, such as emails regarding your account, requests or inquiries, and purchases of products and/or services.
16. Information on the right to object under Art. 21 GDPR
The data subject has the right to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her which is based on a task carried out in the public interest (Art. 6 (1) lit. e GDPR) or on legitimate interests (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR), including profiling based on those provisions. The controller shall no longer process the personal data unless the controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. Where personal data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the data subject has the right to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. Where the data subject objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the personal data shall no longer be processed for such purposes. In the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, the data subject may exercise his or her right to object by automated means using technical specifications.
Shop
Product finder
Highlights and promotions
Newsletter sign-up
Careers
Open positions
Working at Miltenyi Biotec
HR contact
Copyright © 2020 Miltenyi Biotec and/or its affiliates. All rights reserved.
